▍2026 辛辛那提 WTA1000 1/8决赛
斯瓦泰克 6-3 6-3 帕里 · 赛后场上采访
the job done.
拿下了比赛。
Three and three in an hour and a half.
三比三，一小时二十八分。
Just a few seconds shy of that.
只差了几秒钟。
and into the quarterfinals at Cincy
已连续第四年打到这一轮，
for a fourth successive time.
Well, she knows
她知道
that she's had to battle a couple of times,
自己也苦战过几次，
but that's the strongest.
但今天是她状态最强的一场。
Iga, congratulations.
Iga，恭喜你。
Man, it is so fun to watch you play.
看你打球真的太享受了。
I mean, your movement,
你的移动、
your commitment to your shots,
你对每一拍的投入、
your intensity, your focus.
你的强度和专注度。
What were you most happy with today?
今天你对哪一点最满意？
I think that I was solid,
我觉得今天打得很稳，
you know, and even though I
而且即便如此，
had to put more energy into the ball
我还是要在球上多花力气，
because she was playing many slices,
因为她打了很多切削球，
sometimes short, you know,
有时候很短，你知道，
sometimes like that.
有时候又是那种。
So, I needed to really put a lot
所以我真的需要
of effort to be intense
多花些力气去保持强度，
and I'm happy about that because I did it
这一点我很满意，我从头到尾
from the beginning till the end
都做到了这一点，
and I'm happy with how I was, how precise I
而且我对自己那些球
was with these shots.
打得多精准也很满意。
You are such a student of of the game.
你真是这项运动的用功学生。
So, when I tell you
所以我要告诉你，
this is your 30th WTA 1000 quarterfinal,
这是第三十次打到这一轮，
it's your fourth straight here in Cincinnati,
辛辛那提已经连续第四年了，
are those are those milestones
这些算是你会
that you pay any attention to?
留意的里程碑吗？
Are you aware of those things?
你会关注这些数字吗？
Not really.
不太会。
It's always nice to hear that.
听到总是会高兴的。
Usually after the tournament, I like
通常赛事结束之后，我会
to maybe a little bit look at the numbers,
多少去看一眼那些数字，
but during I'm just focused
但比赛期间我只专注
on the next match.
在下一场球上。
It doesn't matter if it's a quarterfinal
不管是这一轮还是第二轮，
or a second round, you know,
都一样，你知道，
I want to I treat every match the same way.
每一场我都想用同样态度打。
So, yeah, but it I I know I'm
所以，是的，不过我知道
my Wikipedia day is going to look good.
我的维基百科页面会很好看。
But you know, the key is to focus
但你知道，关键是专注
on being present and that's how you
在当下，那样
can get to those numbers.
自然就能达到那些数字了。
You know,
你知道，
Iga, a couple of trivia questions.
Iga，几个花絮问题。
We all know that you are the Swifty.
大家都知道你是霉粉，
We know you enjoy Legos,
也知道你喜欢乐高，
but now you're getting a master's degree
不管是这一轮还是第二轮，
in movies from the '9s apparently.
在读九十年代电影『硕士』。
Are you keeping up with that?
你还在跟进吗？
Not not no I mean no because I'm I became
不是不是，是因为我
more you know I'm watching recent
更多是在看，你知道，我在看
movies for the first time in my life.
近期电影，我人生第一次。
But I I am a little bit late
但我确实有点晚了，
because I just watched Oppenheimer.
因为我刚看了《奥本海默》。
So I loved it.
我很喜欢。
I went to the movies to see the Odyssey.
我去电影院看了《奥德赛》。
So I'm being a little bit more, you know,
所以我这次算是，你知道，
on on time this time.
跟得上一点了。
But I love '90s movies.
但我真的很爱九十年代电影。
Like it had they have their their own vibe
它们自成一种气质，
and how they shot them,
拍摄的方式
it was also a bit different.
也有点不一样。
I don't know. It kind of calms me down
说不上来，就是看着看着
to watch them.
会让我平静下来。
So yeah,
是的，
last quick question.
最后一个简短的问题。
My friends and I argue
我和朋友一直在争论
about this all the time.
这件事。
As a voracious reader, is listening
作为一个嗜读如命的人，听书
to an audio book considered reading
算不算读书，
to Iga, fanatic?
Iga？算吗？
No.
不算。
I mean reading
我是说，读书
is literally reading like looking at the letters,
就是真的去看那些字母，
you know.
你知道。
But I've honestly never done
但说实话我从没为了
that for for my pleasure.
享受而听过有声书。
I just used like not audio book but to cheat
我用它只是为了
in school cuz there were some books
在学校应付一下，因为有些书
that I just couldn't read you know I
我真的读不下去，我是说
mean like two of them only like
就那两本，
the only books basically I didn't finish
我这辈子基本上没读完的书
in my life so I needed to listen to them
就只有那几本，所以我得听，
because I don't know
因为你知道
at school you know you have deadlines I
学校总有交作业的期限，
was busy playing tennis you know
我那时候又忙着打网球，
so it saved me quite some time
所以它帮我省了不少时间，
but that's the only time I literally listen
但那也是我唯一一次
to an audio book so yeah
听有声书，所以，是的。
the champion has spoken.
冠军已经表态了。
The debate is settled.
这场辩论到此为止。
Read your bookante.
去读你的书吧。